investis.com 2018-08-13

# Privacy Statement | .INVESTIS

## Who we are

Investis respects your right to privacy and will process personal information you provide in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation, Data Protection Act 2018, the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 and other applicable privacy laws.

We have prepared this Privacy Policy to explain how, why and when we collect data from you.

## Definitions and Interpretation

In this Policy, the following terms shall have the following meanings:

**“personal data”**

| 

means any and all data that relates to an identifiable person who can be directly or indirectly identified from that data. In this case, it means personal data that you give to Us via Our Site. This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the EU Regulation 2016/679 – the General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”); and   
  
---|---  
  
**“We/Us/Our”**

| 

means Investis Limited, a limited company registered in England under company number 03930926, whose registered address is 24 Fashion Street, London E1 6PX.  
  
## What Does This Policy Cover?

This Privacy Policy applies only to your use of Our Site. Our Site may contain links to other websites. Please note that We have no control over how your data is collected, stored, or used by other websites and We advise you to check the privacy policies of any such websites before providing any data to them.

## Your Rights

As a data subject, you have the following rights under the GDPR, which this Policy and Our use of personal data have been designed to uphold:

  * The right to be informed about Our collection and use of personal data;
  * The right of access to the personal data we hold about you; 
  * The right to rectification if any personal data We hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete;
  * The right to be forgotten – i.e. the right to ask Us to delete any personal data We hold about you 
  * The right to restrict (i.e. prevent) the processing of your personal data;
  * The right to data portability (obtaining a copy of your personal data to re-use with another service or organisation);
  * The right to object to Us using your personal data for particular purposes; and
  * Rights with respect to automated decision making and profiling.

If you have any cause for complaint about Our use of your personal data, please contact Us using the details provided under the ‘How Can You Access Your Data’ section and We will do Our best to solve the problem for you. If We are unable to help, you also have the right to lodge a complaint with the UK’s supervisory authority, the Information Commissioner’s Office.

## What Data Do We Collect?

If you register on this site, you will be asked to provide certain information about yourself (such as your name, address, email address and telephone number, login details such as user name and password). We only ask that this information is provided should you want use a service, make an inquiry or speak to us about our products or services. We only collect the minimum data required to carry out your inquiry.

We may also collect some technical data such as your Internet Protocol (IP) address which connects your computer or mobile device to the internet, your login information, browser type and version. This is necessary for Us to allow you to use Our Site. 

Information on cookies can be found in our cookie policy when visiting Our Site. 

## How Do We Use Your Data?

If We do collect any personal data, it will be processed and stored securely, for no longer than is necessary in light of the reason(s) for which it was first collected. We will comply with Our obligations and safeguard your rights under the GDPR **** at all times. 

If you contact Us and We obtain your personal details from your email, through Our contact page or by registering on Our Site, We may use them as follows:

To reply to your email;

  * To contact you for legitimate business interests
  * To contact you about your account and our services
  * To contact you for service-related reasons that you have subscribed to, signed up for, or participate in (e.g. to make you aware of any changes in your subscription, reminding you of a password or username, or about a comment you have made on a website);
  * To fulfil subscription orders, provide information relating to the product you signed up to;
  * To track traffic flows and to make our websites easier for you to use and to better understand how our websites are used;
  * Planning and managing our business activities by understanding aggregated analysis on behaviour and habits;

You have the right to withdraw your consent to Us using your personal data at any time, and to request that We delete it. We provide an unsubscribe option on all of our communications.

If we do process your personal data we may use one or more of the following lawful basis for processing: 

Consent: We may Process your Personal Data where we have obtained your prior, express consent to the Processing (this legal basis is only used in relation to processing that is entirely voluntary – it is not used for processing that is necessary or obligatory in any way);

Contractual: We may Process your Personal Data where the processing is necessary in connection with any contract that you may enter into with us;

Compliance with applicable law: We may Process your Personal Data where the processing is required by applicable law;

Vital interests: We may Process your Personal Data where the processing is necessary to protect the vital interests of any individual; or

Legitimate interests: We may process your Personal Data where we have a legitimate interest in carrying out the processing for the purpose of managing, operating or promoting our business, and that legitimate interest is not overridden by your interests, fundamental rights, or freedoms.

## How Long Do We Keep Your Data?

Investis shall not keep personal data for any longer than is necessary in light of the purpose or purposes for which that personal data was originally collected, held, and processed.

We will always retain your personal information in accordance with law and regulation and never retain your information for longer than is necessary.

When personal data is no longer required, all reasonable steps will be taken to securely erase or otherwise dispose of it without delay.

## Where Do We Store Your Data?

The data that we collect from you may be transferred to and stored at a destination outside the European Economic Area (EEA). It may also be processed by staff operating outside the EEA working within the Investis group or one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the fulfilment of your order and the provision of support services. By submitting your personal data, you agree to this transfer, storing and processing. We will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that your data is treated securely, in accordance with your rights and in accordance with this privacy policy. All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers.

If you register for the alert service, you will need to provide your name and email address. This information will be held by Investis and may be accessed by Investis Corporate Communications PVT. Ltd (a subsidiary of Investis) from its premises in India for administration of the alert service. The information will not be used for any other purpose; it will be stored securely and will not be shared with third parties.

Data security is very important to Us, and to protect your data We have taken suitable measures to safeguard and secure any data We hold about you (even if it is only your email address).

We have put in place security procedures and technical and organisational measures to safeguard your personal information. Access to all internal servers is limited to the specialist IT and Data personnel. 

## How Can You Access Your Data? (Subject Access Request)

You have the right to ask for a copy of any of your personal data held by Us (where such data is held). Under the GDPR, no fee is payable and We will provide any and all information in response to your request free of charge.

If you wish to exercise your rights, or have any questions regarding your Personal Data please contact Investis using the details below. 

Please contact Us for more details at [GDPR@Investis.com](mailto:GDPR@Investis.com) or by telephone on +44 (0)20 7038 9000.

We may require proof of your identity before we can give effect to these rights. ****

## Do We Share Your Personal Data?

To fulfil certain services, we work within the Investis group and also some external suppliers some of which may reside outside of the European Economic Area (EEA). For us to provide this order/ service we may need to share your data with an organisation. We will only share if:

  * it is necessary to honour a contract between you and Investis;
  * we have a legal obligation to share the information;
  * it is in the public interest; 
  * it is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims;
  * it is necessary to protect the vital interests of you or another person.

  * We do not subscribe you to marketing emails without your consent.
  * We do not sell or give away your contact information to any other entities.
  * We do not allow the vendors who help us process transactions or services to sell or give away your information. 

## Links to Other Websites

We sometimes provide you with links to other websites, but these websites are not under our control. Therefore, we will not be liable to you for any issues arising in connection with their use of your information, the website content or the services offered to you by these websites. We advise you to consult the privacy policy and terms and conditions on each website to see how each supplier may process your information. 

## Changes to Our Privacy Policy

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time (for example, if the law changes). Any changes will be immediately posted on Our Site and you will be deemed to have accepted the terms of the Privacy Policy on your first use of Our Site following the alterations. We recommend that you check this page regularly to keep up-to-date.
